<message message-id="v02110103abc3bca7219e@[130.91.88.102]" list="com.listbox.v2.ip" id="24auh2spu7tk6ckr" type="general" date="1995-04-26T05:03:54-04:00" year="1995-01-01" year-month="1995-04-01" year-month-day="1995-04-26" thread-id="24auh2spu7tk6ckr"><headers><envelope-from-line>From farber@central.cis.upenn.edu Wed, 26 Apr 1995 05:03:54 -0400</envelope-from-line><from personal="David Farber" address="farber@central.cis.upenn.edu">David Farber &lt;farber@central.cis.upenn.edu&gt;</from><subject normal="A Pretty Bad Problem -- Forward to PGP User's Guide by Phil">A Pretty Bad Problem -- Forward to PGP User's Guide by Phil</subject><date>Wed, 26 Apr 1995 05:03:54 -0400</date><message-id>v02110103abc3bca7219e@[130.91.88.102]</message-id><mime-version>1.0</mime-version><content-type>text/plain</content-type></headers><normalized-references><normalized-message-id>v02110103abc3bca7219e@[130.91.88.102]</normalized-message-id></normalized-references><body type="text/plain"><para depth="0">
A Pretty Bad Problem
Forward to PGP User's Guide by Phil Zimmerman

</para><para depth="0">by John Perry Barlow

</para><para depth="0">I love irony, and there lies in this book an irony as striking as any I
know. It is this: that a computer program with the cute li'l ol' name of
Pretty Good Privacy, written by an apparently unformidable gnome on a tight
budget, now terrifies a security monolith that required half a century,
uncounted billions of dollars, and the collective IQ's of a few thousand
geniuses to develop.

</para><para depth="0">This book and the software it describes, as brief and modest as its author,
could very well be the root tendril that will grow into the National
Security State and shatter it. It that is true, it's probably only a little
hyperbolic to claim that you are holding a work as liberating as Common
Sense, or, viewed through another set of bunker slits, as socially
disruptive as Mein Kampf.

</para><para depth="0">That doubtless sounds like a pretty disruptive statement itself, but it's
not unconsidered. It seems to me that the combination of distributed
digital technology and robust encryption has brought informatized society
to a very sharp balance point between two lousy choices. On one side lies a
technological foundation upon which the most massive totalitarianism could
be built. On the other is a jungle in which any number of anarchic
guerrillas might hide, upon whom little order could ever be imposed.

</para><para depth="0">Assuming I'm not simply raving here, what leads me to this conclusion? Have
things really gotten this weird? I honestly believe they may have.

</para><para depth="0">At present most of us unwittingly leave a highly visible and nearly
indelible trail in Cyberspace. Every time we make a modern financial
transaction, use the telephone, send an e-mail message, we leave a path of
bits from which anyone who's interested and properly equipped can assemble
the detailed informational ghosts of our naked selves. If you have
something you'd rather hide, don't hide it there.

</para><para depth="0">Furthermore, the tools of surveillance are becoming far more sophisticated
and conducive to centralization. Massive pattern recognition engines can be
applied to the Net from, say, Washington, DC or Beijing, and specifically
tuned to recognize certain kinds of activities.  Or even beliefs.

</para><para depth="0">Any government that can automatically generate an intimate profile of every
one of its citizens is a government endowed with a potential for absolute
power that will eventually, to use Lord Acton's phrase, corrupt absolutely.
Few civil liberties are likely to survive such capacities in the hands of
the increasingly panicky authoritarians who run the embattled old
bureaucracies of the Meat World.

</para><para depth="0">Worse, their panic may be justified. An equally apprehensive and growing
lot of cyber-libertarians now have at their disposal tools as unbalancingly
powerful in their power to conceal as are the other side's in the service
of revelation. One of these sabots goes by the mild name of Pretty Good
Privacy.

</para><para depth="0">Any number of citizens armed with PGP and such of its relations as digital
cash and anonymous Net remailers can simply vanish from the governmental
radar. They are at greater liberty than ever before to conduct any
endeavor, including something that, as Phil frankly puts it at the
beginning of this book, "shouldn't be illegal, but is." They can exempt
themselves from taxes and yet maintain precise accounting records. In many
ways, they can effectively resign from the community of the governed and
enter a condition in which their actions ordered by conscience and culture
alone.

</para><para depth="0">And we may get a chance to find out just how well these are going to work
as the primary templates for social order. There is no question that the
patterns of unwritten code that arise from culture can work when the
society in question is small, simple, or highly homogeneous.

</para><para depth="0">For example, I come from a part of Wyoming where something like the Code of
the West is still more important than the law or its instruments. It works
pretty well. I don't have a key to my house, and through many years in the
cattle business, I signed few contracts and was never knowingly cheated.

</para><para depth="0">Something similar obtains in Japan, a much larger and more complex society
which is nevertheless monocultural enough to resist chaos far more by
general consent than by any order that police might enforce. And it is
nearly crime free.

</para><para depth="0">The emergent social orders of both Japan and Wyoming strongly support the
idea that a less legalistic approach to the vicissitudes of life among the
humans will work. What it less well known is whether it is possible to
return to such a condition and whether truly diverse societies, such as we
have in America, can ordered primarily by cultural norms.

</para><para depth="0">Present evidence from both the former Soviet Union and the former
Yugoslavia is not so promising. After 70 years of the most heroic efforts
to force order by imposed regulation, the great iron lid is off. And it is
no Rousseauvian paradise to which the Russians have returned. They appear
to be governed less by ethics than by criminals who would probably govern
better if they were organized. Meanwhile the Balkans have returned to a
state of tribal bloodshed that indicates that a strong sense of community,
as expressed in cultural immune response, can be more disruptive than
ordering.

</para><para depth="0">But what are the choices? Do we allow matters to continue along their
present technological trajectory, eventually endowing our government (and
practically any marketing organization) with a magnifying window into the
least of our lives? Do we allow ourselves to become intimately vulnerable
to faceless bureaucracies to whom we will be incredibly well known yet
remain faceless ourselves? We have gone too far that way already. But what
can prevent a further tumble toward that dark horizon?

</para><para depth="0">Do we try to hide our trails behind laws (favored by Europeans) that would
define what might be the appropriate contents for a database? Do we endow
government with the ability to define forbidden knowledge? I don't have
much enthusiasm for this solution, which sounds to me rather like having a
Peeping Tom install one's window blinds, I do not trust government with the
ability to regulate information, especially information that contains
within it such a long lever of control as those things about yourself you'd
rather no one knew.

</para><para depth="0">There are always special circumstances - grave matters of national
security, they will insist. - in which it will seem obvious to our
guardians that the sanctity of such laws is secondary to the greater public
interest. Indeed, this is how we have been doing things in America for a
long time. The Bill of Rights continues to apply only when the government
feels no pain from its application.

</para><para depth="0">It's a tough choice, but I think I would prefer to give people the means to
control their own information. I think it is best that this virus of
liberty is loose on the Net.

</para><para depth="0">I would prefer to let my fellow citizens detach their economic transactions
from their identities, despite the looming possibility that an anonymous
economy will consider taxes voluntary. I would even rather extend to people
the general condition of anonymity, hoping they will not use it much,
knowing that without identity, there is little impetus for responsibility,
and that without responsibility, the Social Contract is abrogated.

</para><para depth="0">While I have focused so far on the ability of PGP to conceal, it is the
area of identity that this software may make its most positive
contribution. Even as digital technology can make us to visible, the
absence of real bodies places a garment of ambiguity on everyone who
interacts on the Net. If community requires identity, what is to be done
about the ease by which the virtual can take on one another's identities?

</para><para depth="0">To this dilemma, PGP provides an unambiguous solution: digital signature.
Using the signing techniques enabled here, you can send and receive files
with great assurance that they were generated by their purported authors
and that their contents have not been altered. Once you are in the habit of
authenticating your own words, no one may pretend to speak or act as you.
You can be assured that you will only have to be responsible for your own
actions and not the misdeeds of some phantom wearing your name.

</para><para depth="0">For the rest of what PGP enables, ambivalence is the only appropriate
response. Still, I would at least rather everyone know how to use the tools
whose operation this book describes, though I fervently hope they will be
somewhat circumspect about actually using them. Just as an armed populace
may be more resistant to certain excesses of governmental zeal, so might a
populace armed with the ultimate defensive  weapon, the ability to
disappear, countervail against the all-seeing electronic eye.

</para><para depth="0">We had best be armed with something. It seems certain to me that any
government that can see everything we do all the time will sooner or later
feel compelled to add omnipotence to omniscience, which are, in the Virtual
Age, much the same thing anyway.

</para><para depth="0">Maybe we will feel compelled to start using them. Maybe there will be
anarchy, maybe even chaos. But chaos at least has an open architecture.
Chaos has always been the native home of the infinitely possible. And among
the possibilities I imagine is that human beings will turn out to be
better, less paranoid, less worthy of inspiring paranoia, than many of us
think.

</para><para depth="0">In the end, it doesn't matter much what they think or I think. The genie of
guerrilla cryptography is out of the bottle. No one, not even its maker,
can stuff it back in or keep it within what America laughably calls its
borders. The genie is all over the Net. It's in your hands as you hold this
book. Summon it with a conscience. But be prepared to summon it if you
must.

</para></body></message>