<message message-id="357739D6-CBBF-11D8-90B5-000A9595FFE0@uclink4.berkeley.edu" list="edu.ku.nhm.mailman.taxacom" id="24cp7rapxzp62y57" type="general" date="2004-07-01T17:31:50" year="2004-01-01" year-month="2004-07-01" year-month-day="2004-07-01" thread-id="lpthvafy3ivzqbro"><headers><envelope-from-line>From rlmoe@UCLINK4.BERKELEY.EDU  Thu Jul  1 17:31:50 2004</envelope-from-line><from personal="dick moe" address="rlmoe@UCLINK4.BERKELEY.EDU">dick moe &lt;rlmoe@UCLINK4.BERKELEY.EDU&gt;</from><subject normal="ITIS (an explanation of GBIF's data integration activities)">ITIS (an explanation of GBIF's data integration activities)</subject><date>Thu,  1 Jul 2004 17:31:50 </date><in-reply-to>&lt;f04330118bd0a1c87410c@[172.16.16.129]&gt;</in-reply-to><references>&lt;BA40C59A366A0C44BB24F56BCCAFB3E733B963@bioserver.biology.usu.edu&gt;
            &lt;f04330118bd0a1c87410c@[172.16.16.129]&gt;</references><message-id>357739D6-CBBF-11D8-90B5-000A9595FFE0@uclink4.berkeley.edu</message-id><content-type>text/plain; charset=iso-8859-1</content-type><mime-version>1.0</mime-version></headers><normalized-references><normalized-message-id>357739D6-CBBF-11D8-90B5-000A9595FFE0@uclink4.berkeley.edu</normalized-message-id><normalized-in-reply-to>f04330118bd0a1c87410c@[172.16.16.129]</normalized-in-reply-to><normalized-reference>BA40C59A366A0C44BB24F56BCCAFB3E733B963@bioserver.biology.usu.edu</normalized-reference><normalized-reference>f04330118bd0a1c87410c@[172.16.16.129]</normalized-reference></normalized-references><body type="text/plain; charset=iso-8859-1"><para depth="0">We are implementing a tracked, collaborative system for the Index to
California Plant Names,
available under the Jepson Online Interchange:
<url>http://ucjeps.berkeley.edu/interchange.html</url>.

</para><footer type="signature" hash="13423334529023712919" depth="0">Richard Moe

</footer><para depth="0">On Jul 1, 2004, at 12:59 PM, Peter Stevens wrote:

</para><quote depth="1"><quotepara depth="1">From Mary Barkworth:

</quotepara><quote depth="2"><quotepara depth="2">The failure of IPNI to have developed the kind of collaborative
structure mentioned in an earlier email by someone (sorry - forget
who)
is particularly disturbing in view of the promises made at the
International botanical Congress in St. Louis in 1999.  I hope the
leaders of IPNI will be able to state next year in Vienna that they
have
implemented and made visible information about questions that have
been
raised and addressed concerning particular names. Kanchi Gandhi
provides
fantastic feedback to those of us engaged in the Flora of North
America
project, checking the validity and legitimacy of individual names,
often
in consultation with other members of IAPT's nomenclatural committee.
He
also quickly corrects any of the Gray Card entries that need it.
Gerrit
Davidse at MO is also quick to correct any errors that are brought to
his attention. Unfortunately the questions themselves and the reasons
for the answers given do not appear anywhere, making it likely that
the
same questions will be asked again and again. I know this last is
true;
I have done it myself. It would be nice to be spared the embarrassment
of asking the same question twice - and to spare Kanchi the effort of
looking up his earlier response.  More importantly, no question should
have to be looked into more than once. My understanding from the
presentation at St. Louis was that IPNI would be providing the kind of
information to help ensure that would be the case. Did I misunderstand
or ?
</quotepara></quote><quotepara depth="1">
You did not misunderstand - that seemed to me the neatest aspects of
the whole project.  As I inderstand things (having left IPNI when I
moved to MO), providing that kind of cumulative documentation remains
a goal.

</quotepara><quotepara depth="1">Peter S.

</quotepara></quote></body></message>